Gilberto Ramirez | Software Engineer



gramirez.softwareengineer@gmail.com | 🐨 github.com/Gilberto-Felipe | 💇 LinkedIn: gilbertoramirez-swe





Summary

I'm a Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in Fullstack positions. C# .NET Core, React, SQL. I have experience in the development of Content Management Systems and ERP applications. I'm looking for backend or full-stack roles.

Experience

Full-stack Engineer | DPR Construction | 2021 - present [2 year] | Remote

Javascript/ES6, React, C#, Web APIs with .Net Core and Entity Framework, SQL Server, Git, TFS, Reactstrap, Material UI (MUI), Formik, YUP, PrimeReact, Chrome DevTools, ActiveBatch

- Human Resource Planning Management System: Developed and did maintenance for 30 modules. This application is used by 50+ HRPs.
- Management System for SMS: Developed UI generic components and modules for scheduling and logging messages.
- Asset Management System: The system keeps track of asset leasing. Developed 8 modules. Delivered the first version in four months.
- Integrated, maintained, and documented Web APIs to third-party applications.
- Mentored two colleagues to introduce them to projects in both React and .NET Core Web API. Pair programming to debug applications.
- Coordinated the migration of 409 jobs from different technologies (SQL, SSIS, Powershell, and C# executables) to the scheduler ActiveBatch. The effort lasted 6 months and involved 7 engineers from different teams.

Full-stack Developer Intern | GHAPPS | 2019 - 2020 [1 year] | Colima, Mexico

HTML5, CSS, Javascript/ES6, JQuery, PHP, MySQL, Git, Bootstrap, AdminLTE

• Developed a Content Management System. It provides information for Loro Fan, the mobile app of the University of Colima soccer team. Developed the database, the login, UI views, and the backend. The app has 100 downloads for Android.

Other skills: Python, TypeScript, PHP, Linux System Administration, GitHub, Power BI

Education

Bachelor degree in Software Engineering | University of Colima | 2017-2021 | Colima, Mexico C# Courses | Plural Sight | 2021 | Online: Beginning Collections, Building an API with ASP.NET Core. Python for Everybody Specialization | Coursera | 2020 | Online Bachelor degree in Philosophy | Regina Apostolorum | 2007-2011 | Rome, Italy